2024年9月，德国德累斯顿的一座桥梁毫无预警地轰然坍塌。
In September 2024, a bridge in Dresden, Germany, collapsed without warning.
六个月后，柏林的一条环城公路
6 months later, a ring road in Berlin had to be closed
在检查人员发现一处意外扩大的裂缝后，不得不临时封闭。
after inspectors found a crack that had grown unexpectedly.
该路段随即被拆除，交通一度陷入混乱。
The section was immediately demolished, causing traffic chaos.
类似的例子不胜枚举——
We could go on
这不过是德国交通骨干网络积重难返的两个缩影。
because these are just two examples of how far the backbone of Germany's transport network has declined due to neglect and poor maintenance.
但援手已经伸来：
But help has arrived
一项高达5000亿欧元的基金正致力于振兴德国的基础设施，受益范围远不止桥梁和铁路。
in the form of a€ 500 billion euro fund
aimed at revitalizing the country's infrastructure
一项高达5000亿欧元的基金正致力于振兴德国的基础设施，受益范围远不止桥梁和铁路。
with more than just bridges and railways set to benefits.
这是一笔庞大的资金，
It's an enormous sum of money,
按理说应该足以一劳永逸地解决这些问题。
one that you'd think
should be able to solve these problems once and for all.
然而，令人难以置信的是，人们仍在追问：这够吗？
And yet, incredibly, people are asking, will it be enough?
德国是全球第三大经济体，
Germany is the world's third largest economy,
但光看它基础设施的现状，你恐怕根本不会这么认为。
but you wouldn't know it from the state of some of its infrastructure.
是的，德国拥有全球最庞大的高铁系统之一。
Yes, it has one of the largest highspeed rail systems on the planet.
当然，前提是它真的能准时运行。
When it actually runs on time, that is.
还有德国高速公路（Autobahn），
There's the autoban, too,
行驶体验也相当不错——只要你没有被突然改道，或者没有因为无处不在的施工而被迫减速。
which is great when
you're not being diverted suddenly
行驶体验也相当不错——只要你没有被突然改道，或者没有因为无处不在的施工而被迫减速。
or made to slow right down due to the constant road works.
之所以施工不断，原因之一是
One reason there's so much of that
许多支撑公路的构筑物早已急需修缮，甚至需要整体替换。
is because many of the structures that support those roads are in dire need of repair
or due to be replaced.
数以万计的桥梁已被认定需要升级改造，
Tens of thousands of bridges have been identified as needing upgrades
情况最糟糕的将在未来十年内面临拆除。
with the worst cases facing demolition over the next 10 years.
但情况并非一直如此。
But it's not always been this way.
二战之后，大量基础设施遭到摧毁，
We had the situation that a lot of the infrastructure was destroyed after World War II
这在很多情况下反而给了我们重新开始的机会。
and it gave us the chance to start a new in many cases.
所以如果回望七八十年代，
And so we had quite a modern and advanced infrastructure
你会发现那时德国的基础设施相当现代，相当先进。
if you look back to the 70s and 80s.
>> 克里斯蒂安·贝特格尔博士是柏林应用科学大学（HTW Berlin）的教授，该大学坐落于德国首都柏林。
>> Dr. Christian Bertgur is a professor at HTW Berlin, a university of applied sciences based in the German capital.
>> 九十年代德国统一，
>> We had a big push in infrastructure
那是一次基础设施建设的大推进。
with uh the unification of Germany in the '90s.
我认为，至少在西部，当时基础设施的质量相当不错。
I think the infrastructure was quite good
东部也获得了大量资金，
in the west of Germany at least. A lot of money was provided for
用于升级东部基础设施，
upgrading the infrastructure
因为战后那里的改造程度远不及西部。
in the east that had not been upgraded in the same way after the war as in the west.
但自那以后，情况实际上就一直在走下坡路。
But since that time, it has been deteriorating actually.
不过话说回来，情况本可以更糟。
Still, it could be worse.
确实存在各种缺陷，但通常在造成大问题之前就会被发现并修复，
Yes, there are defects, but they're usually spotted and fixed
然后一切照常运转。
before things then carry on as usual.
不过最近，出现了几个相当严重的例外，
But recently, there have been some pretty big exceptions to that,
其中一起事故轰动了全世界。
including one failure that made news around the world.
在德国，官方正在调查
Here in Germany, officials are investigating
东部城市德累斯顿一座桥梁的局部坍塌事故。
the partial collapse of a bridge in the eastern city of Dresden.
>> 可以看到，整个夜晚都有车辆经过这座桥，所幸卡罗拉桥倒塌时桥面上没有任何人。
>> You can see there had been traffic on the bridge throughout the night, but thankfully the Dresden Bridge was empty at the time.
我们得到的消息是，这座混凝土桥的其他部分此时也存在坍塌风险。
We're told other parts of the concrete bridge are also at risk of a collapse at this point.
>> 2024年9月11日凌晨
>> Just before 3:00 a.m.
近三时，德累斯顿的卡罗拉桥（Carolabrücke）突然坠入易北河。
on September 11th, 2024,
the Corolla Bridge in Dresden fell suddenly into the River Ela.
这座桥建于1971年，早于两德统一，
Built in 1971 before reunification,
供行人、骑行者和有轨电车通行——
the concrete structure was used by pedestrians, cyclists, and trams,
倒塌前几分钟，刚好有一辆电车驶过。
including one that had just passed over it mere minutes beforehand.
所幸无人伤亡，
While no one was hurt,
但坠落的残骸封堵了河道，致使船只数月内无法通行。
the resulting debris blocked ships from accessing this section of the river for months.
由于易北河上还有另外两座桥，
Having two other bridges on the river
绕行路线很快得以确定。
meant detours were quickly found.
尽管如此，失去这座桥
But still, the loss of this one
还是让市民在城内出行变得更加麻烦。
has made traveling around the city much more difficult than it should be.
坍塌发生后，这当然令人震惊，对交通影响很大，但交通还是找到了其他路线。
After the collapse, it was of course shocking and also influencing the traffic much, but the traffic found other ways.
斯特凡·马克斯是德累斯顿工业大学的教授，
Stefan Marx is a professor at Dresdon's Technical University.
他受市政府委托，撰写了一份关于卡罗拉桥坍塌原因的报告。
He was commissioned by city officials to write a report on the reasons for the Corolla Bridge collapse.
平均来说，如果需要穿越城市、横跨这条河，出行时间大概会多出四到五分钟。
In average, we have four to 5 minutes um uh higher traffic time if you need to cross the city uh and if you need to cross the river.
当然，在早晚高峰期，这个时间损耗要高出许多。
Of course, in rush hours, the time effort is much higher.
是啊，在某些天里，出行时间甚至会多出半个小时。
Yeah. So then you can even spend half an hour longer in some days.
>> 这次事故不仅切断了一条重要的交通线路，
>> Not only did the incident sever a major transport connection,
这座桥还承载着市政管道，
the bridge also carried utility pipes,
导致许多居民无法使用暖气和热水。
leaving many people without heating or hot water.
斯特凡发现，随时间积累的材料疲劳，
Stefan discovered that material fatigue over time
以及氢致应力腐蚀（hydrogen-induced stress corrosion）引发的裂缝，是导致大桥垮塌的根本原因。
and cracking caused by hydrogen-induced stress corrosion
接下来让他进一步解释。
are what led to the bridgeg's failure.
But we'll let him explain in a little more detail.
问题早在施工阶段便已埋下——
It was activated already during the construction time
当时空气中的水汽带有酸性物质，
due to a moisture which was in the air
而这些酸来自德国各地住宅煤炉供暖燃烧产生的烟气。
containing acid
and the acid was from the heating of the coal heaters in all the flats in in Germany
当含酸的雾气飘落到
and so if you have this acid fog in the air
预应力钢材上，损伤过程便随之开始，
it was coming down to the pre-stressing steel
这一损伤过程就此被诱发——
this damage process was in induced
所以这座桥从投入使用之初，安全系数就已大幅降低，
so the bridge
而这一点当时无人知晓。
had already from the beginning of its lifetime
a very much reduced safety factor
而这一点当时无人知晓。
which nobody really knew.
好了，既然你现在已经是氢致应力腐蚀领域的"专家"了，你可能想知道：接下来呢？
So now that you're an expert in hydrogen induced stress corrosion, you might be wondering what's next?
怎样才能进一步了解这些科学知识呢？
How can I learn more about these sciency subjects?
如果你有这样的想法，我完全理解，
And if that's you, then I get it because I too love mastering
因为我也热衷于弄清楚事物的运作原理，
how things work and learning how they can go very, very wrong
以及它们是如何出问题的——就像刚才那个例子。
like in the example we just heard.
但为了不让我的脑细胞像那座桥一样崩塌，
But to ensure my brain cells don't crumble like that bridge,
我借助 Brilliant 来保持知识的鲜活。
I have Brilliant on hand to help keep my knowledge intact.
通过他们的"科学思维"课程，
Through their scientific thinking course,
你可以循序渐进地探索结构是如何被设计成经久耐用的。
you can discover how structures are built to last step by step.
通过实验重量、梁和齿轮，
By experimenting with weights, beams, and gears,
你在动手实践和解决问题中学习——
you learn by doing
这正是强化科学能力的最佳方式。
and problem solving,
which is the best way to strengthen your science skills.
我也发现他们的课程相当有趣，
I found their courses a lot of fun,
而且，如果科学不是你的菜，也完全不用担心——他们还有数千门数学、编程、数据分析和人工智能课程。
too. But if science isn't up your straza, then don't worry
想在 Brilliant 免费学习整整30天，请访问 brilliant.org/theb1m。
because they've got thousands of lessons in maths, programming,
data analysis, and AI as well.
想在 Brilliant 免费学习整整30天，请访问 brilliant.org/theb1m。
To learn for free on Brilliant for a full 30 days, go to brilliant.org/theb1m.
扫描屏幕上的二维码，
Scan the QR code on screen
或点击视频简介中的链接。
or click the link down in the video description.
他们还为我们的观众提供了年度高级订阅八折优惠，
They've also given our viewers 20% off an annual premium subscription,
让你无限畅享 Brilliant 上的所有内容。
which gives you unlimited daily access to everything on Brilliant.
好了，言归正传，咱们聊回德国那不怎么"出色"的基础设施。
But until then, let's get back to Germany's not so brilliant infrastructure.
不难理解，
You can see why this incident
这次事故为何引发了全国上下对其他桥梁状况的广泛担忧。
sparked a lot of concern about the condition of other bridges across the country.
而德国人没等多久，
And Germans didn't have long to wait
下一个麻烦就来了——
for the next problem.
2025年3月，柏林一座高速公路桥被紧急拆除，
March 2025 saw a highway bridge in Berlin quickly demolished
原因是一处裂缝的扩展速度超出了预测。
after a crack had widened faster than predicted.
尽管此举最终避免了一场灾难，
Although this ultimately prevented disaster,
许多柏林市民仍然认为，事情本不该发展到这一步。
many Berliners felt it shouldn't have been allowed to get to this stage.
在全新项目方面，德国的声誉也大打折扣。
On entirely new projects, Germany's reputation has taken a bit of a hit
首都的勃兰登堡机场因官僚主义和管理混乱，一拖就是数十年才得以开放。
as well. Brandenburgg Airport, also in the capital,
famously took decades to open because it was marred
首都的勃兰登堡机场因官僚主义和管理混乱，一拖就是数十年才得以开放。
by a bureaucracy and poor management.
其他仍在推进中的大型工程也面临同样的困境，
The same goes for other mega projects that remain ongoing like Stutgart 21
比如斯图加特21工程和慕尼黑新城铁（S-Bahn）线路，
and Munich's new Esban line, both of which are hugely expensive
两者都耗资巨大，严重滞后。
and heavily delayed.
不过，终于有些好消息了。
However, there is at last some good news to report.
2025年3月，德国总理弗里德里希·默茨宣布了一项大规模支出计划——
In March 2025, German Chancellor Friedri Mertz announced a massive spending push.
高达5000亿欧元（约合5500亿美元）
A staggering €500 billion, that's around €550 billion US,
已被划拨用于全国各地的基础设施升级。
has now been earmarked for upgrades right across the country.
其中3000亿欧元将拨给联邦政府用于基础设施项目，
300 billion of that will be given to the federal government for infrastructure projects.
1000亿欧元分配给各州，
A h 100red billion has been set aside for individual states
剩余1000亿欧元用于气候相关投资。
and the remaining 100 billion is for climate related investments.
但如果你以为这笔钱会一次性砸下去，那就想多了。
But it's not all being splurged in one go if that's what you're thinking.
这笔支出将分摊在
This spending is going to be spread
12年内逐步花完。
out over a 12-ear period.
一年额外花5000亿欧元，
It makes no sense to spend one year 500 billion extra euro
下一年又两手空空——这根本说不通。
and then next year is is empty again.
我们需要一个长远的眼光。
We need a long-term perspective.
所以这是好事。
So this is good.
但话说回来，每年也不过就400亿欧元。
But same time of course it's only 40 billion euro per year.
而且这笔钱不只用于桥梁——
And this means it's also spent not only in bridges,
还涵盖能源基础设施、
it is energy infrastructure,
水利基础设施、学校、
water infrastructure, schools
道路交通以及铁路交通。
and street traffic as well as railway traffic.
事实上，我们来看一些实际数据。
In fact, let's bring up some actual data on that.
根据德国复兴信贷银行（KfW）
According to a summary from Germany's stateowned development bank, KFW,
的一份摘要，这是资金在未来几年内的去向。
this is where the funds will be going in the first few years.
可以看到，超过一半的资金将投入交通基础设施，这并不令人意外。
And it's no surprise to see that more than half the money is being invested into transport infrastructure.
显然，这是一个相当宽泛的类别，
Now, obviously, that's a pretty broad category,
目前尚不清楚这笔资金将如何具体分配，
and it's not yet clear exactly how that pot of money is going to be divided up,
但德国铁路（Deutsche Bahn，DB）似乎很可能会拿到最大份额。
but it appears likely that Deutschean, Germany's national railway company, will get the lion share.
一家经济研究机构称，新基金的第一个完整财年（即2026年），已有近190亿欧元专门划拨支持德国铁路。
One economic research institute claims that almost €19 billion has been set aside
to support DB in just the first full year of the new fund,
一家经济研究机构称，新基金的第一个完整财年（即2026年），已有近190亿欧元专门划拨支持德国铁路。
which is 2026.
这想必会受到热烈欢迎，
That surely will be appreciated
因为德国铁路运营方表示，到2034年需要多达1500亿欧元
as the operator has stated it needs
来修缮和现代化升级铁路网络。
as much as 150 billion euros
to repair and modernize the network up to 2034.
德国铁路的财务问题由来已久——
Financial issues with German railways are nothing new.
长期资金不足，可靠性也每况愈下。
The system has been underfunded for decades and has become increasingly unreliable.
但如今，这一问题已经严重到让重大国际项目不得不搁置。
But now it's got to the stage where big projects, important international projects, are being put on hold.
布伦纳基底隧道（Brenner Base Tunnel）的北部接线段——
The northern access route of the Brena Base tunnel,
建成后将成为世界上最长的地下铁路连接线——
which will be the world's longest underground rail connection when it completes,
目前因资金限制悬而未决。
is in limbo over financial constraints.
这条隧道线路本身连接奥地利和意大利，
While the line itself connects Austria and Italy,
但从慕尼黑接入的其中一条支线已被暂时叫停。
one of the lines that's going to feed into it from Munich has been temporarily paused.
>> 我们曾承诺届时建好一条线路，
>> We promised them to have a line ready by then
但当奥地利准备好时，那条线路将无法如期完工。
uh which will not be ready when when Austria is ready.
我们对瑞士也许下了同样的承诺，当他们开通哥达德基底隧道（Gotthard Base Tunnel）时同样如此。
We promise the same
thing to the Swiss
我们对瑞士也许下了同样的承诺，当他们开通哥达德基底隧道（Gotthard Base Tunnel）时同样如此。
um when they open the Gotard Basel.
目前我们谈论的竣工时间大约是2045年前后。
Uh right now we talk about completion somewhere 2045 or so.
丹麦正在修建一条连接法斯托岛和费马恩岛的新隧道，
The Danish are building a new tunnel connecting the islands
但当他们完工时，
of Fa and Feiman and there won't be a connection
德国这边根本不会有任何接线就绪。
available on the German side when they are ready.
所以，认真环顾四周，我们确实让周围的邻居大失所望——
So if if you really look around, we are really frustrating our neighbors
这真是一个令人沮丧的局面。
and uh so it's really a very disappointing situation.
>> 或许在交通领域之外，情况稍微没那么悲观。
>> Perhaps things are a bit less bleak outside the transport sector.
嗯，也许吧。
Well, potentially yes.
预计将有若干能源项目分得那1000亿欧元的一部分，
Several energy projects
这将有助于德国向更加气候友好型的能源供应转型。
can expect to be handed a portion of that 100 billion euro chunk
which will help Germany transition to a more climatefriendly power supply.
德国计划通过加大对氢能基础设施和可再生能源的投资来实现这一目标，
Investing more in hydrogen infrastructure and renewables is how it plans to do this.
而且已经抢先一步，
And it's already made a head start
取得了一些令人叹为观止的工程成就。
on that
with some truly amazing feats of engineering.
以南联输电线（SuedLink）为例——
Take the Sud link for example,
这是一条大型地下高压直流输电线路，
a massive underground high voltage power link
建成后将成为同类工程中全球最长的。
that will become the longest of its kind in the world when it completes.
全长超过500公里，
At more than 500 km long,
它将把德国北部风电场产生的电力输送到南部地区。
it'll transport electricity generated by wind farms in the north of Germany to the southern end of the country,
这一过程中需要克服一些棘手的障碍：
which requires finding a way around some difficult obstacles.
一条5公里长的隧道正在开凿，
A 5 km tunnel
以便电缆能穿行于易北河20米以下，
is being excavated so the cable
并穿越地下水位较高的区域。
can pass 20 m under the Ela River
and through areas with high levels of groundwater.
对，就是卡罗拉桥倒塌的那条河。
Yes, that's the same river where the Dresden Bridge collapsed.
好，问题来了：德国为何现在能花这么多钱？
Okay, but how is it that Germany is able to spend all this money now?
为什么早些年不行？原因在于一项叫做"债务刹车"（Schuldenbremse）的机制。
And why couldn't it have just spent it all before? Well, it's all to do with something called the debt break.
这是德国宪法中的一条规定，将联邦政府的新增借贷上限
It's a constitutional rule in Germany that caps new borrowing from the federal government
设定在GDP的0.35%。
at 0.35%
多年来，
of GDP. Over the years,
这一规定让德国无法通过大规模举债来投资新基础设施。
that's prevented Germany from loaning large sums of money to invest in new infrastructure.
但这项新基金是规则的一个例外——它被安排在债务刹车的框架之外，
But this new fund is an exception to the rule. It's been organized outside of the debt break,
这意味着政府可以大手笔地花钱。
meaning they can splash out in a big way.
之所以现在可以这样做，是因为德国的债务与GDP之比
And the reason it can be done now is that Germany's debt to GDP ratio
远优于法国、意大利、英国和美国。
is a lot better than
countries like France, Italy, the UK, and the US.
然而，一些人对新资金与常规拨款之间的配合方式提出了质疑——
However, some have raised concerns about how the new money will complement the usual funding.
换句话说，地方和中央政府在正常年份本应提供的资金，将如何处理？
In other words,
what would have been supplied by the local and national governments in a normal year.
德国经济研究所发现，德国铁路获得的190亿欧元注资，
The German Economic Institute found that Deutsche Barn's 19 billion euro injection comes at the same time
恰恰与联邦预算中削减的近140亿欧元铁路投资同步发生。
that
almost 14 billion of rail investments have been cut from the federal budget.
所以，整体增量远比表面看起来要少。
So it's less of an increase overall than it first appears.
道路桥梁和数字化升级的情况也类似。以铁路为例，他们在预算上动了个手脚：
And it's a similar case with road bridges and digital upgrades. What you can see for rail for example is that they employed another trick in the budget
原本用于铁路和基础设施的资金被从核心预算中抽走，
that actually whatever money they had so far for railways and for infrastructure was taken out of the core budget
改由这项新基金来承担。
and now to be financed from this new fund.
所以这不是新增资金，不过是资金挪移——
So not additional but just shifting money
这样做腾出了核心预算的更多空间，让政客们有余地讨好选民。
and that gives you more room in the core budget
for all kind of wonderful things uh that politicians want to give to their voters.
另外还有一个问题：钱不是唯一的症结所在。
There's also the fact that money isn't the only problem.
正如前面提到的，这里的项目经常陷入官僚主义的泥淖，
As we mentioned earlier, projects here often get bogged down in bureaucracy
加上熟练工人本就短缺。
and there's a shortage of skilled workers.
如果这些问题得不到解决，德国建设新基础设施、维护已有设施的能力
If these issues aren't sorted, then Germany's ability to build the infrastructure and repair what it's already got,
只会越来越弱。
it's going to get even harder.
维护工作对政客来说极其无聊，但它至关重要。
Maintenance is completely boring for politics, but it's essential.
如果我们不维护基础设施，最终一定会乱成一锅粥。
If we don't maintain our infrastructure, we will end in a mess for sure.
如果任由现有基础设施退化，
And if we allow a degradation of our existing infrastructure,
我们将失去整个社会赖以运转的根基——无论是商业活动，还是其他任何方面。
we will really lose our basis for everything
in in the society, for the business, but also for everything else.
话虽如此，在5000亿欧元计划宣布之前，
Now, despite everything we've just said, before the 500 billion euro package was announced,
情况也并非一直那么糟。当大型公路基础设施升级项目在这里得到妥善规划时，往往完成得相当出色。
things weren't always that bad. When big highway infrastructure upgrades are properly planned here, they can be very impressive.
毕竟，德国依然拥有一批世界顶尖的工程师，
After all, Germany does still have some of the world's best engineers
能够和任何人一样出色地完成大型工程任务。
that can pull off a big job as well as anyone.
比如多特蒙德附近的A45林斯多夫高架桥，
Like with the A45 Rinsdor fire duct near Dortmund,
始建于20世纪60年代。
which was originally built in the 1960s.
到2020年代，它出现了无法简单修复的结构性问题，
By the 2020s, it developed structural issues that couldn't be simply repaired,
最终迎来了一场你这辈子都难忘的精彩爆破拆除。
which led to one of the most satisfying demolitions you're ever likely to see.
太棒了！
Wonderbar.
>> 2022年东段被炸毁后的三年，
>> 3 years after the eastern section came down in 2022,
轮到将新桥"滑"入就位了。
it was time to slide its replacement into position.
对，我们说的就是"滑入"。
Yes, we said slide.
新结构在不影响行车的道路旁建造完成，
The new structure was built away from the live road
然后通过一种叫做"横向平移"的工法与原有路面对接。
and joined onto it through what's called a transverse shift.
聚四氟乙烯（Teflon）板作为滑动垫安装在专门准备好的轨道与基础底板之间。
Teflon plates acting as sliding pads were installed between the specially prepared tracks and the base of the foundation.
随后，借助24台液压千斤顶，
Then with the help of 24 hydraulic jacks,
工程师们以每小时1英里的速度将桥体推移，平移约20米后与相邻桥段完美对接。
engineers were able to move the bridge at a speed of 1 mph
until it covered a distance of 20 m and slotted in next to its neighbor.
这是一项令人叹服的成就，
It was an astonishing achievement
也证明了只要资金到位，德国同样能建造出世界一流的基础设施。
and showed that if the money is there, Germany can build big infrastructure as well as anyone.
但让我们把目光拉回到德累斯顿的那座桥。
But let's go back to that bridge in Dresden for a moment.
自从那次事故发生以来，
Because ever since that incident happened,
许多人心头萦绕着同一个问题：接下来会怎样？
the question on many people's lips has been what happens next.
好消息是：那座桥将会重建。
You'll be pleased to know that the bridge is going to be replaced.
虽然最初估计重建过程可能需要十年，
And while initially they thought that process could take 10 years to complete,
但最新的预测乐观许多。
the latest estimate is a lot more agreeable.
目前已有四家公司参与竞标，争夺卡罗拉桥继任方案的设计权，
Four companies are now competing to design the successor to the Corolla Brooker
优胜者将于2026年年中揭晓。
with the winner set to be announced in mid 2026.
这意味着新桥的外观目前尚未确定，
That means we don't yet know what it's going to look like,
但一些细节已经透露。
but some details have been revealed.
德累斯顿市希望新桥既具现代感、又能与历史城景和谐融合，
The city of Dresdon wants it to be a contemporary structure that also blends seamlessly into the historic cityscape
计划于2028年动工，2031年竣工。
with construction beginning in 2028 and finishing in 2031.
距坍塌仅七年——
That's a mere 7 years after the collapse,
不过，这相当于中国建造世界最高桥梁所用时间的两倍。
or twice as long as China took to build the world's highest bridge.
好在，他们终究会完成的。
Still, at least they'll eventually get it done.
我们必须把这次对城市的冲击，转化为城市发展的契机。
We have to shift the shock and the impact to the city to an advantage for the city.
我们现在有机会，以一种非常好的方式，重建城市的心脏地带。
We have now the chance to rebuild the heart of the city in a very good way.
无可否认，德国曾经引领全球的基础设施，正在走向崩塌。
There's no denying that Germany's once worldleading infrastructure is crumbling.
过去几年来，支持这一判断的证据已经清晰得不能再清晰。
Over the last couple of years, the evidence to support that has been clear as day.
但如今我们清楚了问题的根源，也有了解决的计划。
But now we know why it's happening and there's a plan in place to get it fixed.
德国人有望很快终结那些
Hopefully, Germans will soon be saying our feet to send to all those
嘲笑他们建造和维护能力的笑话。
jokes about their inability to build things or keep them maintained.
但前提是，那些承诺的资金必须用在正确的地方。
But only if the money that's been promised is used in the right way.
否则，一切可能又将回到原点。
Otherwise, it could be back to square.
本视频由 Brilliant 赞助。
This video was sponsored by Brilliant.
别忘了点击下方链接去看看他们。
Don't forget to go and check them out at the link below.
你们支持我们频道最好的方式之一，
One of the best ways that you guys can support the work we do at this channel
就是花时间去关注我们视频的赞助商。
is by taking the time
to go and check out our video sponsors.
所以，如果你能这么做，那就太好啦！
So, if you can do that, that would be fantasticish.
一如既往，如果你喜欢这期视频，
And as always guys, if you enjoyed this video
想看更多来自这个工程建设权威频道的内容，请点击订阅按钮。
and you want to get more from the definitive video channel for construction,
hit that subscribe button.